[dramatic music playing]
[explosion]
[gunfire]
[dramatic music playing]
[explosion]
[dramatic music continues]
Goddamn it. Evans!
Be careful.
Sorry. Top. It's these damn roads.
It's fucking pea soup out there.
Didn't you. um. tell me you was
a professional truck driver in Chicago?
Detroit. First Sergeant. and yeah.
Well. then. why don't you
quit your yapping
and let's get these
resupplies to Schoenberg
and we'd be done?
Yeah. Top.
Done would be real nice.
Everybody's saying we
could be home by Christmas.
What the fuck are you
talking about. Evans?
These bastards just broke
through our front line
like an ax through butter.
and they planned in the worst weather
so we couldn't get air support.
They ain't stupid.
And it's dangerous thinking it's over.
It ain't goddamn over.
and I don't know if it'll ever be over.
Just keep driving. Evans.
We gotta be there by 08:00.
[ominous music playing]
God!
-[groans]
-Fuck!
[engine whirring]
We gotta get out of here.
Let me check on it.
[engine whirring]
Stop. stop. stop!
Evans. it's not gonna work.
-[distant explosion]
-[Evans] Fuck.
We're stuck. guys.
Lancaster. help me with this winch.
[soldier] What's going on. First Sergeant?
[Lancaster] On it. Top.
[vehicle approaching]
-[soldier] What's that. Sarge?
-Don't move.
[engine whirring]
[gunfire]
[SS soldier in German] Be careful!
[distant explosion]
[guns cock]
Fire!
[US soldier groans]
[gunshot]
[in German] Go.
Let's finish this.
[gunfire]
[in German] What was the name
of the Black American in Berlin?
[SS soldier] Jesse Owens.
They all look the same.
But they don't all run the same.
[SS soldiers laugh]
We're ten hours late. Let's go!
[dramatic music playing]
-Let's go.
-I hate Lucky Strikes.
-Shut your mouth. Faster!
-Yes. sir.
Let Schmidt lie there.
We don't have time for him.
Yes. sir.
I said get in!
[engine whirring]
[dramatic music playing]
[knocking on door]
[door lock clicking]
[colonel. in English] Mrs. Caldwell?
Yes.
Hi.
My name's John Castle.
I'm a colonel in the United States Army.
I got your name and address from Galvin.
Yes. what can I do for you?
Well. I'm here to talk about
your pension plan. ma'am.
Do you work with Galvin?
I... I do.
But ma'am. I promise
this... this won't take long.
99th Infantry.
99th Division. 324th Engineers.
Hmm.
Battle of the Bulge.
That's correct.
Hmm.
Yeah. my son.
my son was there too. 761st.
[Castle] It's quite a unit. I heard.
They ah...
Colonel Castle. you said
you worked for Galvin?
With them. not for them.
Well. my lawyer says that
I'm not supposed to be talking
to anybody that works with Galvin.
Is that coffee that I smell. ma'am?
Yeah. I just...
I just put on some. Would you like some?
Like my life depends on it.
I can't believe Galvin Industries
has given away my whereabouts like that.
Well.
there was a lot of persuasion
and a little sweet talk.
I assure you. it didn't come easy. ma'am.
They're a very serious corporation.
Very. very serious people over there.
Oh. I know that for sure.
They're very serious
about not paying me my pension.
Thank you.
-That's why I'm here. ma'am.
-Is that right?
Yes. ma'am.
Well. I have been
threatening them for years.
They know that I don't have the money
to take them to court.
Are you some kind of army lawyer?
No. no.
But I know some of the folks
over at Galvin.
and I do know that they
hold you in high regard.
[scoffs] Me?
-[Castle] Mm-hmm.
-Really?
Top of the line employee.
Yeah. that's what they said.
top of the line employee.
Their words. right there in your file.
Not that I need anyone to tell me. though.
I know.
You know?
Hmm.
Firsthand.
You don't mind. do you?
Old habit.
Help yourself.
[Castle] Cheers.
["I'll Be Home For Christmas"
playing on radio]
[Top] Hey. you two.
K-rat's on the truck. let's go.
Miller. what the fuck are you doing here?
[Ramirez] Hey. you heard him.
move that shit out.
-[Miller] All right. I'll...
-Hurry the fuck up.
Hey. Ram. I might need
your help with this.
-Top.
-Sir.
-How much time do we have?
-[Ramirez] Get this shit out.
Like 30 minutes. sir.
[Ramirez] Anybody seen Miller?
Cash. Cash!
-Cash!
-[Cash] Sir.
-Get over here.
-[Ramirez] Anybody seen Miller?
-Yes. sir.
-We're gonna get you treated.
You're going back with the colonel.
and then probably on a steamer home
with that million-dollar wound.
Congratulations.
To hell with that. sir.
We're nowhere near done here.
Well. you are.
This is a horrible time to leave. sir.
The company needs me.
Yeah. Well. I guess
we'll just have to win the war
without you then.
Probably faster. actually.
Yeah. Cash. You're the unit
egg ball anyway. [chuckles]
Remind me who you are again. green boy.
And you burn the Lucky Strike logo first.
Yeah. yeah. all right.
-Sir.
-Hmm.
Captain Castle.
everybody knows that
you qualified for deferment.
You got a point to make?
I do.
I mean. here you are. Captain.
Hmm. right. truth. justice.
and the American way.
Exactly. we're both here to do our part.
Right.
You lost three fingers. Cash.
so you're going to the hospital.
and the goddamn colonel's driver
is gonna take you there.
Feel honored.
-Yes. sir.
-Good morning. sir.
Let's get inside.
It's so cold. I think
my nuts fell off two miles back.
Yeah. you're telling me.
Uh. what's Charlie Company's status?
We have full sections
and individual engineers
mining and blowing up bridges
where they can.
I also got some guys on the front line.
Other than that. we're
pretty much ready to roll.
All right. well. we got Able and Baker
already out there with their M1s.
so I'm counting on Charlie Company.
Okay. guys. get the maps out.
[Top] Hey. Ram. grab our maps.
-Moving. Top.
-[explosion]
-[Ramirez] Here you are. sir.
-If there's one thing
the Krauts are good at. it's making noise.
-Yeah.
-All right. Aventi. turn Lassie off.
Yes. sir.
[music stops]
All right. no time for small talk.
This road here between
Lanzerath and Elsenborn.
now that's about what.
five miles from here. would you say?
Seems right. sir.
I know it. sir.
Yeah. it's a little under that. maybe.
Okay. well. we need you to
block that road this morning.
All right?
German counteroffensive has
been going on for three days.
and it is massive.
Hitler's probably jacking off
because he's running the same
game plan in the Ardennes
that he ran four years ago.
and it's working. again.
But we're not gonna let the Fuhrer
have the glory. all right?
We're gonna stop these bastards down
and make sure they get
nowhere near our fuel depots.
There's one more thing.
It's the 1st SS Panzer-Division
coming down that road.
[Ramirez] Damn.
Used to be Hitler's bodyguards.
The worst of the worst.
You boys have never fought
anything like them. all right?
No one in the 99th has.
I can promise you that.
Right. now. these guys. they are not...
They're not soldiers. all right?
They're fucking murderers.
Just two days ago. some soldiers
from the 285th surrendered.
threw down their weapons.
put their arms up.
and the SS lined them up
and mowed 'em down
right there on the spot. just like that.
Jesus.
And that has been happening nonstop.
So when it comes to the SS.
there are no rules.
There is no international law.
You get the chance.
you take these fuckers out.
-Am I understood?
-[group] Yes. sir.
And these monsters.
they actually brand themselves
with a tattoo up under their arms.
Imagine giving yourself
the mark of the devil.
We'll get this road cut off. sir.
I will supervise it personally.
How much time do you need?
Thirty minutes to get us there. sir.
and then I'd say about two hours
to set it up. give or take.
I'm taking.
Okay.
-[explosion]
-Okay. all right.
Fantastic.
Let's get it done. boys.
Let's see what you can do.
[Top] Yes. sir.
Cash. where are you?
Sir.
All right. grab your gear.
You're coming with me.
I'm taking you to the field hospital.
-Thank you. sir. but I think I...
-Cash. no buts.
Get your ass in the fucking jeep
like the CO told you to.
God's sake. all right?
You can't even hold
your own dick to take a piss.
Grab your shit. let's go. all right?
Take this order!
-Come on. go!
-[Cash] Yes. sir.
[Top] All right. boys.
we need about a hundred blocks of TNT...
All right. by the time you guys are done.
the battalion will have cleared out.
So we'll keep the frequencies open
so you'll know where to rejoin.
-You got it. sir.
-All right. and remember.
our sons of bitches are better
than their sons of bitches.
-Right.
-[Ramirez] Aventi.
make sure we have extra
batteries for Lassie.
Good luck. sir.
[Top] All right. boys.
we gotta load up that deuce and a half.
-Let's go. fast. fast. fast.
-[explosion]
-Murph.
-[engine cranks]
-[Murphy] Sir.
-How much TNT we have left?
We've got about a hundred pounds.
But we got plenty.
-All right. load it up.
-Yes. sir.
[dramatic music playing]
[soldiers chattering]
[Top] Let's go. let's go. let's go.
-Come on. come on. come on.
-[Miller] Coming.
[Ramirez] Miller. get that
stuff on the truck right now.
Get it up here.
[Top] Come on. come on. come on.
We're good to go. sir.
Fucking cold.
Let's go.
-Look out for them mines.
-[chuckles]
[engine whirs]
[dramatic music continues]
Dauntless 06. Romeo. Dauntless 06.
This is Derrick 06. Romeo. Do you...
Hey. Miller. you and me are on mines.
I'm gonna fuse 'em.
You check 'em and pack 'em.
Aventi. how's that radio check?
I'm working on it.
[truck rumbles]
-Murph!
-Murphy!
I'm sorry. sir.
You do realize we have
400 pounds of explosives
back there. right. Murph?
At least those guys
will go before we do. sir.
Good to know you're always
looking out for the guys.
Call the captain.
If it's not up and ready.
he's gonna kill me.
Hey. Top.
you ever actually set one
of these things up before?
Somehow. you fumble fucks make it here
calling yourselves engineers.
[Miller] I don't even know
what these types of mines are made of.
Sulfuric acid. and nitric acid.
and dimethyline.
It has a molar mass of 287. Top.
Sir. you mind if I ask
you a personal question?
Sure. why not?
I heard you and Cash talking.
Is it true. you were
an agricultural engineer back home?
Yeah.
So you were like fixing
irrigation systems and all that?
Yeah. that's right.
So you qualified for an exemption.
Yes. I did.
So. how did your wife
feel with you signing up?
Okay. Murph. this interview is over.
Just keep your eyes on the road. okay?
Sorry. sir.
[radio operator] Derrick 06. roger.
This is Dauntless 06. roger.
I have you loud and clear.
How do you read me. over?
[Aventi] Loud and clear. over.
[radio operator] Roger. Derrick 06.
Good luck out there. No mercy.
Stop these assholes cold. 06 out.
We got 'em. guys. we got 'em.
You got a photo of your wife. sir?
I bet she's a looker.
I'm not showing you
or anyone else a photo of my wife.
We all know how that goes.
[groans softly]
[engine whirring]
We can't be there already. can we?
-Oh. shit.
-[engine stalls]
-What?
-Not now. man.
It's the damn fuel pump again.
Fuck. Come on. baby. come on.
Fuck!
You didn't handle this in the rear?
[Murphy] The engine's flooded again. sir.
-[distant explosion]
-How long?
It'll need like an hour.
-An hour?
-I'm sorry. sir. I'm sorry.
Fuck.
All right. it's okay. it's okay.
We're on foot. Let's go.
-[Murphy] We're getting out. sir.
-[Castle] Yep.
[Top] Shut the fuck up. I'll find out.
-Top.
-[Top] Sir.
Flooded.
Fuck. flooded again. All right.
Looks like this trip's over.
All right. sir. Let's go. boys. let's go.
[Miller] Reminiscing about the beaches
of Puerto Rico. Ram?
I'm from the Upper West Side. Miller.
I'll take a New York winter
over this shit any day.
[Murphy] You guys think that's bad?
Imagine how those poor bastards
felt in Stalingrad.
Yeah. it was so cold there.
the guys' bowels were exploding
when they tried to take a dump.
[Aventi] Hey. Cap.
Yeah. what is it?
If I die from taking a shit.
don't put that in the letter to my mom.
You got a deal. AV.
[Top] Oh. don't worry. Aventi.
I'll be writing your letter.
It's gonna be a real beaut.
[explosion]
All right. guys. let's move it on out.
-[Castle] Aventi.
-[Aventi] Yeah.
[Castle] No shame in passing Lassie off.
[Aventi] I'm good. sir.
I think this is it. sir. yeah.
[Castle] Okay.
Let's get it started with
these six trees right here.
Got it.
[explosion]
Jesus Christ. what the fuck?
88s. boys. brought out the big eggs.
Yeah. and a goddamn
Macy's parade of Panzer's
coming down this road.
so let's get it blocked.
-[explosion]
-[Murphy] Oh. shit!
Let's get it done quickly.
[Top] All right. Ram. that tree.
[Ramirez] Already on it. Top.
[Top] Murph. start unpacking this shit.
Aventi. Miller. that tree.
-[Top] Let's go.
-[Miller] Got it.
-[Ramirez] Come on. boys.
-[Top] Miller. Aventi. here.
[Ramirez] Top. I need those
wires run here now.
[Ramirez] Murph. you almost
done with those mines?
[soldiers chatter]
[Top] On it.
Okay. Murph. this one's gonna be 18.
[Murphy] Yes. sir.
And how are you guys doing on that abatis?
-Almost done. sir.
-Actually. sir. it's "abatie."
[Ramirez]
Actually. it's "abatee." dumbass.
It's French.
Hey. Murph. bring that det cord.
Yeah. I got it.
-[gunshot]
-[Ramirez] Fuck. fuck!
Snipers!
-Murph
-[Miller] What the fuck?
-[Ramirez] Murphy!
-[Top] Stay back.
Murph! Murph!
[gunfire]
Murph!
-Stay back.
-Fuck. fuck!
[Ramirez] Get down! Get down. Aventi!
[Aventi] Where's he hit at?
We can't leave him here!
Miller. get down!
Damn it.
[gunfire]
-Fuck!
[gunfire continues]
I see 'em. sir. nine o'clock. 300 meters.
Yeah. I see 'em. sir.
It sounds like an MG34.
Okay. we're gonna have
to take this bastard out.
-[gunfire]
-Ramirez!
-Yes. sir.
-You're on me.
[Ramirez] Ready when you are. sir.
-Hey. sir. let me go.
-No. no.
I need you to finish this.
We'll let you know when we're clear.
-Ready?
-[Ramirez] Moving.
-All right. go!
-[Top] Got you covered. sir.
-[Aventi] We've got you guys.
-[Ramirez] Move. move. move!
-[gunfire]
-[dramatic suspenseful music playing]
[gunfire continues]
[whispers] There's two.
[gunshots continue]
[whispers] Yeah. got it.
You good. Cap?
Yeah. I'm good.
[gunfire continues]
[groaning]
[dramatic suspenseful music continues]
[dramatic suspenseful music intensifies]
[whispers] Ram.
[mouthing] On three.
[mouthing] One. two...
-[SS soldier] Grenade!
-[explosion]
[Ramirez panting]
That was fucking beautiful. sir.
All clear. all clear!
Just make sure these Kraut fucks are dead.
-[rifle clicks]
-Whoa. easy on the ammo.
Just get in there.
I don't care what they say about you. sir.
You're all right.
[Castle] Yeah. just check 'em out.
[Ramirez] Kraut piece of shit.
[German soldier speaking German]
-[Ramirez] What?
-[speaking German]
Shut the fuck up.
[speaking German]
What the fuck is he saying. sir?
He wants you to finish him.
[Ramirez snorts. spits]
I'll oblige.
[soldier speaking German]
What the fuck is this?
Grenade!
-[Ramirez] Sir. get back!
-No!
[explosion blasts]
No. no!
Fuck!
[shouts]
[distant explosion]
[groans]
[vehicle approaching]
Oh. shit.
[ominous music playing]
[heart beating]
Come on. get out of there.
Come on. come on. Hide. hide. guys.
Shit.
Come on.
Oh. come on.
Come on. guys.
Okay. okay. okay.
[heart beating intensifies]
[ominous music continues]
Come on. come on.
Shit!
Oh. fuck.
[heart beating intensifies]
[gunfire]
Son of a bitch.
[gunshot]
[Castle screaming]
[groaning]
[somber music playing]
-[distant gunfire]
-[distant explosions]
[distant explosion]
[explosion]
[distant explosions]
[Castle grunts]
[dramatic music playing]
[grunting]
[shouts in frustration]
[shouts in pain]
[breathes heavily]
Shit.
Ah!
[distant explosions]
Come on.
[engine stalls]
Come on. please. please.
Come on.
[SS soldiers chattering in German]
[radio operator] Derrick 06. Derrick 06.
Are you still with us?
Derrick 06. over.
[radio stops]
[distant explosion]
[door opens]
[soldier groans]
[both groaning]
[both continue groaning]
[Castle panting]
[distant explosion]
Dauntless 06.
This is Derrick 06. over.
Any Dauntless?
Dauntless. this is Derrick 06. over.
[radio operator] Derrick 06.
this is Dauntless 06. roger.
Send status. over.
Roger. Dauntless.
Mission accomplished.
Current situation. five KIA.
I'm WIA.
Vehicle's hard broke.
I need some help. over.
[radio operator] Roger.
Derrick. understood.
Send position. over.
06 Derrick. grid as follows.
Able. fox. two. seven. five.
eight. niner. two. over.
[radio operator] There's
a hell of a lot of heat
between you and us.
You need to get to rally point
Elsenborn on your own.
No. Copy. Dauntless. wait.
Wait one.
06. roger. this is Derrick.
It's... That's too big of a hike.
I'm walking but confirm
there's no closer stragglers
I can move to. over.
[radio operator] I don't
know who we have down there
but we can't deal with this now.
We're under intense artillery fire.
Um...
Dauntless 06.
I say again. we have five KIA.
[radio operator] I get it. I'm sorry.
Come up on comms top of every hour
and use SOI encoding in the future.
Keep your radio battery alive.
It's your lifeline now.
Out.
[pensive music playing]
[groaning]
[wolf howling]
[chicken clucking]
[breathing heavily]
[groans]
[gasping]
[wind howling]
I'm gonna make it.
Come on.
[dramatic music playing]
-[door opening]
-[man speaking French]
American. American. American.
American?
America. please.
[man speaking French]
[both grunting]
[Castle. in English] Okay.
[man speaking French]
[Castle] Okay.
[water sloshing]
[woman speaking French]
[man speaking French]
[woman] Hmm.
[woman speaking French]
[man speaking French]
Uh-huh. [speaking French]
[speaking French]
[in English] Okay.
-[speaking French]
-Mm-hmm. Yeah. yeah.
Yeah?
[Castle groans]
-[speaking French]
-Yeah.
Okay.
-Oh.
-[speaking French]
[in English] Yeah.
[Castle] Come on.
[Castle sighs]
[woman speaking French]
[in English] I don't... I don't understand.
Rabbit.
-[speaking French]
-[in English] Food.
-Rabbit.
-Yeah.
Yeah. yeah. I'm hungry. yeah.
-Okay.
-Yeah.
[speaking French]
[women speaking French]
Oh.
Merci.
[explosion]
-[woman gasps]
-[dog barking]
[Castle] Yeah.
I know. it's scary. right? Yeah.
It's scary. yeah.
-This... house.
-Mm-hmm.
-On the map.
-Ah.
Uh...
Ici.
-Here? "Asi?"
-Ici.
-"Esi?"
-Oui.
Okay. thank you.
All right.
-All right. come on. Lassie.
-[radio static]
Come on. girl.
Dauntless 06. over.
Dauntless...
Any station on this net. over.
[vehicles approaching]
Mama.
Mama!
Dauntless 06.
Dauntless 06. this is Derrick 06. over.
-[woman speaking French]
-[Castle] Goddamn it!
[woman speaking French]
[Castle] Ah. yeah.
[vehicle engines whirring]
[SS soldier shouts in German]
[woman speaking French]
-[glass shatters]
-[dogs barking]
[SS soldier speaking German]
[speaking German]
[in English] Fuel depot.
Fuel? [speaking French]
[speaking German]
[dog barking]
-[woman speaking French]
-[SS Soldier speaking German]
[woman speaking French]
-[dramatic music playing]
-[speaking German]
[woman speaking French]
[in English] Fuel depot!
[SS soldier speaking German]
-[woman speaking French]
-[in English] Fuel.
[girl] Mama?
[woman speaking French]
[woman. in English] No.
[speaking German]
[in English] No.
No.
-[gunshot]
-[girl screams]
[gunfire]
[girl crying]
Hey. hey. hey. hey.
Shh. shh. shh. shh.
Come on. we gotta go. we gotta go.
Get down there. You'll be okay.
[girl sobs]
[gunfire]
[Castle] Oh. shit.
[vehicle engines whirring]
[Castle] No.
-I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
-[SS soldiers yelling]
Oh. shit.
[SS soldiers speaking German]
[SS soldier speaking German]
-[gunfire]
-[SS soldier groans]
Come on. come on.
Let's get out of this.
Okay.
Ah. shit.
[engine whirring]
-[SS soldiers yelling]
-[gunfire]
[bullets ricocheting]
Ah.
Shit.
Come on.
Come on. John.
Keep digging.
Come on. come on.
Come on.
Fuck.
Come on. come on.
Shit! Come on.
Come on down right.
Come on. come on.
Come on. you damn dog.
Turn back. come on.
Come on.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Castle screams]
[music ends]
[distant explosion]
[groans]
[high-pitched ringing]
Oh. fuck.
[grunts]
Come on.
Oh. man.
I am not dying in this Kraut machine!
[pants]
Piece of shit.
Come on. come on.
Come on.
Oh. God.
Come on. God.
If you're not helping the Yankees.
again. please. please get me out
of this motherfucker tank!
Oh. ah!
Thank you.
[groans]
-[panting]
-[distant explosions]
[dog whimpers]
Oh.
[groans]
Fuckers.
Hello?
Ah!
Hey.
Hi. Hey.
Are you okay?
Ah. that's a stupid question.
Of course. you're not okay.
Yeah.
Look...
the Americans are coming. okay?
They'll...
They'll help you.
Okay. okay.
Come on. John.
[pistol clicks]
I'm sorry.
I should have come out faster.
You keep that for protection. okay?
And don't tell anybody about that
or they'll court-martial me.
[distant explosion]
[groans]
[sobbing]
Come on. John.
Come on.
Come on. come on.
[slow. dramatic music playing]
[engines whirring]
[dramatic music intensifies]
[Castle] Dauntless. my current position
is Oboe. William. Peter.
Oboe. William. Roger. Sugar.
[radio operator] Okay. looks like
you still have a big trek up here.
-Maybe...
-[radio crackles]
The Krauts are all over. I say...
[radio crackles]
We cannot get to you.
You made that clear last time.
Uh...
I got the SS crawling all over me.
Please advise.
[radio operator]
Look. we're trying to hold
our fucking position here. Derrick.
All hell's coming down.
Stay in the same vector. I'm out.
Goddamn it!
Ah!
[ominous music playing]
[distant explosions]
-[engine whirs]
-[vehicle approaching]
[vehicle slows. stops]
[SS soldiers speaking German]
[SS soldier groans. laughs]
-[SS soldiers speaking German]
-[zipper zips]
[rifle cocking]
[SS soldier speaking German]
-[knife squelches]
-[groans]
[SS soldiers speaking German]
[engine revs]
[sighs]
[distant explosions]
[distant explosion]
[kettle whistles]
What the hell?
[footsteps approaching]
[grunts]
[Castle grunts]
-[impact thuds]
-[kettle whistles]
[SS soldier speaking German]
[dramatic music playing]
[dramatic music intensifies]
[SS soldier speaking German]
[speaking German]
[door closes]
[floor creaking]
[fire roars]
[SS soldier screams]
[dramatic music playing]
[SS soldier groaning]
[dramatic music intensifies]
[explosion]
[distant explosions]
[pensive music playing]
[Castle] Any station...
Any station on this net?
This is Derrick 06.
Any Dauntless. over?
[radio operator] Dauntless.
how you holding up?
[Castle] Dauntless. I...
I steered clear of Bellingen.
I think I'm back on track.
traveling north
by northwest to rally point.
[radio operator]
They're surrounding our southern side.
which means you're behind enemy lines.
They're pounding us.
Find shelter.
[Castle] No. negative. Dauntless.
There is no shelter.
I need to keep moving.
I'll take my chances to get to you.
[radio operator] Just be careful.
1st SS is gonna unload
everything they have.
Good luck.
[groans]
Oh. my God.
Oh.
Jesus.
[soldier coughs]
Oh. hey.
Hey.
Hey. hey.
Are you okay?
Oh. man.
Other than being shot twice.
All right. Sergeant.
Yeah.
Hey. what's your name. huh?
Maren.
Maren. that's your first name?
-[explosion]
-Pierce.
Pierce.
The truck work?
-Yeah. but it's stuck.
-It's stuck.
-[Pierce coughs]
-Okay.
Okay. okay.
Look. I'm gonna...
I'm gonna get this thing unstuck. okay?
-Any water?
-Water?
Oh. yeah.
Yeah. sorry.
Yeah. of course.
Here.
Come on. come on.
Come on. here.
Yeah. there you go.
Oh. shit.
Okay.
Oh. man. I need a rope
or something to get this out of here.
Shit.
-You gotta use the winch.
-Winch.
Oh. there's a winch. good.
Okay. good call.
[grunts. groans]
Okay. I'm gonna get this thing.
[Pierce coughs]
[Castle blowing]
Come on. man. you need
to talk to me. okay?
Pierce. you talk to me. okay?
Fuck.
So. where are you from?
[Pierce] Bridgeport.
Ah. Connecticut. [groans]
[grunts] Never been.
I hear it's...
I hear it's nice there.
Is that true?
[Pierce] Yeah. I think you'd like it.
Pierce. Pierce.
-[Pierce coughs]
-Come on.
Come on. pal. stay with me.
How long you been out here. huh?
Long time.
All right. long time.
All right. all right.
Tell me. are you ready to go home?
[explosion]
[high-pitched ringing]
-[object clicks]
-[groans]
[explosion]
[foreboding music playing]
[music fades]
[horse chuffs]
-[Castle screams]
-[horse whinnies]
Shit!
[horse whinnies]
[gunfire]
Shit!
[Castle screams]
-[gunfire]
-[explosions]
Stop. please.
Stop.
Please. God.
[Castle screams]
Help. please. Take me home.
Hunter.
[inaudible]
[Castle coughs]
[groans]
[chain rattling]
[dog barking]
[soldier] Hey. stop! Fido. quiet. hey!
Quiet. hey. American.
Who are you?
Captain Castle. 324th engineers.
Sergeant Bellingham. sir. 14th...
-[Castle] Agh!
-Ooh. ooh.
I got you. I got you.
Here. let me help you with your radio.
[Castle] Ah. yeah. yeah.
You okay?
-Looks like you took some shrapnel.
-Yeah.
[Castle] Geez. what happened here?
[Bellingham] Our willy's...
Willy's got mortared. I think.
I don't really remember what happened.
What was that hell show anyway?
Oh. I don't know.
Yeah.
[Bellingham] That looks
pretty severe. sir.
We should... we should
get you sitting down.
I got you. sir.
-[Castle groans]
-There you go.
So.
where were you headed before this?
I need to get to the 99th Division command
and get a package to the commander.
General Lauer?
-Yes. sir.
-Yeah.
Okay.
I don't know their position now. do you?
No. I don't.
I'm only in contact
with battalion. not division.
You have a priority frequency for him?
If you do. we could... we could try him.
It's above my pay grade.
Right.
We'll try the 324th then.
That'd be great.
I have to courier these reports on them.
Yeah. Yeah. you said that.
Progress of the Third Army.
What. Patton's not allowing
scrambled lines between armies now?
I can't see anything.
Can you turn that on... on for me?
[Bellingham] Let's see if it even works.
Patton. huh?
Great general.
Huge pain in the ass.
[Bellingham] Yes.
Thanks.
What about you. sir?
What are you doing out here? You uh...
you get separated from your unit
or something like that?
-Yeah.
-[dog panting]
Yeah. something like that.
Are you hungry. sir?
It's tuna loaf.
[Castle] Oh. thanks.
[Bellingham mutters to dog]
Oh. good boy.
Good boy.
Nice trophy.
Huh?
You got a Luger.
I've been trying to find one
of those since I got here.
[Castle] Oh. yeah. yeah.
I just gotta find that station.
[Castle] Oh. come on. old girl.
Come on. please.
I got nothing.
[Bellingham] I think
the battery's still alive.
Do you mind. sir?
Yeah. she's pretty beat up.
You a... you a radio guy?
Let me see.
Lassie. huh?
Yeah. yeah. man.
Our radio operator named her that.
Seemed fitting how reliable
she's been till now.
Yeah. I'm more of
a Rin Tin Tin man myself.
[radio hisses static]
[chuckles] She may be reliable after all.
-How about that?
-Yeah.
-Oh. good work. knew it.
-She's receiving.
-Good work.
-Yeah.
Okay.
Oh. shit. sir. You're bleeding out.
[Castle] Yeah. I know.
-That's not good.
-Mm-mm.
[Castle] Let's just focus on
getting out... out of here.
Yeah. you have a point guy at the 99th?
No. no. no. no.
I was supposed to report to HQ directly.
[sniffs] I have the sealed positions
maps with me. but I don't...
I don't know shit besides that.
All right. Any station?
Any station on this net?
Any station?
This is Derrick 06. over.
[radio hissing. tuning]
Yeah.
Nobody's home.
[distant explosion]
Krauts.
-They love to fight at night.
-Yeah. they can't...
They can't wait to.
to die for their fatherland.
[Bellingham] That's true.
I'll tell you why.
[Castle coughs]
Because they don't have much to live for.
Yeah. sorry.
Yeah. thank you. sir.
[Bellingham breathing deeply]
Like. when you say they
don't have much to live for.
I mean. from their point
of view. I don't know.
Hitler's given them a hell of an economy.
He gave them the Olympics.
And if I'm being honest.
every country has its...
undesirables.
I mean. look at what we did
to the Indians.
Look. don't get me wrong. okay?
Hitler's a... a monster.
He's a vile beast.
But when we don't understand them
and we don't understand what drives them.
then we underestimate them too.
Mm-hmm.
[radio operator] Derrick 06. Derrick 06.
do you copy. over?
Copy. copy. copy.
This is Derrick 06 actual.
[radio operator] Derrick.
we've secured Elsenborn.
We're trying to release
some assets to get to you.
Any idea where you are at all. over?
Ah. yeah. hold on. hold on.
[Castle] Okay.
Now. listen. I think
we're on the south side of...
Hittenberg maybe.
[radio operator] Roger. Did you say we?
Are you with somebody. over?
Yeah... yeah. I got a...
What is it. what is it?
Bellingham. Belling...
I got a Sergeant Bellingham here
who's assigned to deliver
maps to the 99th HQ.
You got a position for him?
[radio operator]
Okay. let me check on that. over.
[Castle] Copy. this way. Copy.
So. where are you from. huh?
Milwaukee.
Does that make you a Cubs
or a White Sox guy?
No. no. no. I'm not a...
not a big baseball guy.
So football then?
-Definitely. yeah.
-Yeah.
Yeah. that's my game.
Naval-Army game is like a national holiday
in my household.
[Bellingham] We gather around the radio
and listen to the game every year.
How long you been in?
God. I lost track of that.
They had me down in Africa driving tanks
until someone spilled the beans
and told 'em I was a engineer back home.
Now I'm up here blowing up bridges.
You got a girl back home?
[laughs] No.
No. I got my "Dear John"
two weeks into basic.
Yeah.
How about you?
[chuckles] Kids?
Yeah.
Yeah. one. my son. Hunter.
Looks like you'll be seeing him soon.
Yeah. that's the plan.
My wife lost her brother at Midway.
so I better get home.
Oh. you will. sir.
We're gonna get you back.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna take care of business.
I'll be back.
[coughs]
[Fido yawns]
[distant explosions]
[pensive music playing]
[ominous music playing]
Uh...
Uh. who'd you say you take
again in the Naval-Army?
[Bellingham] What?
[radio operator] Derrick 06. do you copy?
Yeah.
Yeah. copy. copy.
[radio operator]
Okay. prepare to write down.
Yeah. go ahead.
[radio operator] SOI.
Baker. Charlie. X-ray.
yoke.
love.
able.
tare.
uncle.
Over.
[Castle] Yeah.
Copy.
[ominous music continues]
[Castle] Hey. do me a favor.
Tell the guys.
tell the guys to step on it. okay?
I'm in bad shape.
[radio operator] Godspeed
to you. Captain Castle.
Out.
Godspeed.
[Castle] Here. here's the info.
-That's the position of HQ.
-Thank you. sir.
[chuckles]
You don't know
what you're looking at. do you?
Like I said. it's...
it's above my pay grade.
It's an SOI encoding.
SOI. signal operating instructions.
But you wouldn't know that.
Sir.
please put the weapon down.
You mean my... my trophy?
Sir.
you've been badly injured. okay?
-You're not thinking straight.
-Shut up!
No one... no one taught you
how to light up a Lucky
the right way. did they?
-Please. sir.
-You see. we do this
so we don't leave
breadcrumbs for you assholes.
Please. sir.
Next time. think of that. fucker.
They warned us about scumbags like you.
born in America yet killing Americans.
You think because I smoke
a cigarette a different way
that I'm a Nazi sympathizer?
Not a sympathizer. a Nazi!
I told you I'm not SS.
I'm a fucking American.
Oh. yeah. really?
-Yes. sir. I'm...
-Show me.
Show me you don't have a SS tattoo
underneath your arm.
[radio operator]
Derrick 06. Derrick. copy. over?
-[Fido barking]
-[gunshot]
[gunfire]
[Castle groans]
[Fido barking]
[coughs]
Two left.
[gunfire]
[Fido barking]
-[gunfire]
-[Fido whimpers]
[gunfire]
[suspenseful music playing]
[gunshot]
[gunfire]
-[gunshot]
-[Bellingham groans]
[groaning]
[Castle grunts]
[radio operator] Derrick 06.
this is Dublin 06 Rider.
Over.
-Derrick 06. Derrick 06. do you copy?
-[radio crackles]
Over.
[on radio] ♪ I'll be home ♪
♪ For Christmas ♪
♪ If only in my dreams ♪
[engine whirring]
[Castle] Where's Lassie?
Are you okay. sir? Can you hear me?
[Castle] Where. where. where...
Where are we?
You're doing great. sir.
We're almost at the field hospital.
[Castle] Where's the radio?
Right here. sir.
[nurse] I'll be back shortly.
Captain Castle?
Yes. sir. he's right over there.
-Good afternoon. Captain.
-[Castle groans]
Good to have you still with us.
Sir.
At ease. son.
Relax.
I'm General Lauer.
Nice to meet you. sir.
From what we've been able to ascertain.
you've really been through it.
[Lauer] Left a lot of dead Nazis
in your wake.
And that abatis you created
stopped them in their tracks
and bought us some precious hours.
[Castle] Yeah.
But that final position you ended up in...
I don't even...
remember or know what happened. really.
Those goddamn Krauts blew
the hell out of that place
because they were trying to create
a path for themselves to Elsenborn.
It's just your bad luck you were there.
I want you to know we're putting you in
for the Silver Star captain.
You damn well deserve it.
Oh. I...
What about the. uh.
the soldier. the guy where you found me?
Yes. he was SS posing as an American.
He's dead. You got him.
And our intel tells us
that they were trying to find
the location of General Lauer.
so you were right in shooting the bastard.
Right.
How did you know. by the way?
Oh. he. uh...
he said some wrong things.
And he didn't burn
the brand off his Luckies.
Sin number one.
Well. three cheers
for shitty German training.
You look like you could
use a bit more rest.
so see you soon.
Sir. I... I don't...
All my men are dead.
Yes. I know.
and I'm very sorry.
Yeah. I just don't think
that I deserve any kind of medal.
Luckily. that's not for you to decide.
Well. with all due respect. sir.
I just gotta say no. thank you.
I'm an officer
and keeping my men safe. that...
that's my job. and I failed that.
That's really what you think.
that your job is to keep your men alive?
Yes. sir.
Well. that's. uh...
That's a crock of shit. son.
Soldiers die in war.
Your job is not to keep your men alive.
Your job is to keep my mother alive.
Your job is to keep your mother alive.
Your job is to keep
all our children alive.
So...
with all due respect. Captain.
you can take your no thanks
and you can shove it up your ass.
A bit of a miracle. those things. huh?
Hmm. bit more reliable than a miracle.
Get some rest.
[sighs]
[soldier] Get the deuce and a half ready!
[Cash] Hey. sir.
[Castle] Cash.
-Good to see you. partner.
-[Cash] Good to see you. too.
[Castle] Yeah.
I saw your nurse. sir.
I didn't fare as well.
Yeah.
I guess rank has its privileges.
Yeah. I guess it does. [chuckles]
[Cash sighs]
I heard the men died well. sir.
Yeah.
Yeah. that they did.
You survived.
I guess we can be grateful for that.
Not sure survival's all
it's cracked up to be. Cash.
They're sending me home. like you said.
Going to a hospital in Paris
and on that steamer.
What about you?
Do you finally get to go home
to that beautiful wife and boy of yours?
Yeah.
[Cash] They're saying
there may be a lot more snow.
Yeah. it sure isn't gonna
make this fight any easier.
Both sides. though. right?
I'll see you later. sir.
-Here.
-No. keep it.
He really said Naval-Army game?
He did.
Everybody in America knows
it's the Army-Navy game.
Americans fighting for the Nazis.
Dear Jesus. I had never
heard of that before.
Yeah. there were rumblings
about turncoats and spies.
[Mrs. Caldwell] Yeah.
But I was kind of like.
you know. how unlucky
do you really have to be
to run into one of them?
Very unlucky.
Hmm.
But lucky enough to make it through.
Well. there was definitely luck.
But without Lassie...
Oh. you think I built...
[Mrs. Caldwell scoffs]
No. [chuckles]
No. no. no. no. no. no.
No.
I've worked on
the assembly chain at Galvin.
and I did build the 300s.
but there's no way of knowing
for sure that I built...
Production unit number 5204.
assembly line four.
station seven. batch 52.
Date of issue. 11/5/1943.
And in charge that day.
Rose Caldwell.
You memorized it.
Like my children's birthdays. ma'am.
That might have been
the sturdiest radio in the war.
Hmm.
That was the goal.
Take a look at this.
[Mrs. Caldwell sighs]
Hmm.
Nine thousand.
Thank you. Colonel.
I have been trying to settle
with these folks for years.
For years.
Nothing doing.
-How did you...
-Well. I just told them
they should do the right thing by you.
an outstanding worker.
as a matter of principle.
Now that's a load of horseshit.
Well...
I may have told them
that since I'm in charge
of all radio equipment
purchases nationwide
for the United States Army that...
they should heed my request.
lest I look for another supplier.
[sighs]
Eighty years from now...
everyone will know the history
of what happened in that battle.
But will they understand it?
I hope they do.
[soft music playing]
Tomorrow. we'll play.
but you have to go to bed. okay?
[Hunter chuckles]
Okay. all right.
Who loves you. pal?
-[Hunter] Dad.
-That's right.
Go off to bed.
All right. this time for real now.
[soft music continues]
[light switch clicks]
♪ Show mercy to the hero ♪
♪ A pale horse haunts his fated road ♪
♪ Depleted heart ♪
♪ And his nerves on fire ♪
♪ And soldier on the only way he knows ♪
♪ Show mercy ♪
♪ To the hero ♪
♪ Who fights a fight he didn't choose ♪
♪ Show mercy ♪
♪ To the hero ♪
♪ There's nothing left but his soul ♪
♪ To lose ♪
♪ He carries the weight of survival ♪
♪ He sleeps with the ghosts ♪
♪ Of wrong and right ♪
♪ He remembers each breath ♪
♪ He thought was his last ♪
♪ And the empty stare ♪
♪ Of every endless night ♪
♪ Show mercy ♪
♪ To the hero ♪
♪ Who fights a fight he didn't choose ♪
♪ Show mercy ♪
♪ To the hero ♪
♪ There's nothing left but his soul ♪
♪ To lose ♪
♪ They'll give him a parade ♪
♪ And sing his name ♪
♪ He'll do his very best ♪
♪ To smile and wave ♪
♪ Nobody understands ♪
♪ The sorrow and the shame ♪
♪ Pale horse will come to see ♪
♪ Hero lives in agony ♪
♪ The hero lives in agony ♪
♪ Show mercy to the hero ♪
♪ There's nothing left but his soul ♪
♪ To lose ♪
[plaintive horn music playing]
[epic dramatic music playing]
[music fades]